Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
A number of space colonies
had been built around the Earth...
...and people lived their lives
in this second home to humanity.
The space colony Side 3 proclaimed itself
the Principality of Zeon.
Seeking to impose its dictatorship
over all of humanity...
...it waged a war
against the Earth Federation.
After evading a Zeon attack...
...the White Base escaped from
the space colony Side 7...
...and landed on Earth.
And now...
Sayla's Agony
Still unable to contact Federation HQ...
...the White Base heads west
across Central Asia.
The young crew is exhausted.
All they can do is carry out
their assigned duties.
Still can't find it?
You should sleep more.
Amuro, you are a pilot, you know.
Can't see anything.
It's confirmed by astronomical observations.
We're here at the appointed place,
at the appointed time...
...yet there's no word from General Revil?
We left the communication circuit open...
They wouldn't send it by radio anyway...
...considering we're in
Zeon territory.
So, someone's going to walk here...?
To the middle of this desert?
Stop kidding around, Kai.
We're all tired at this hour.
Sayla, make sure everyone continues
to monitor for aircraft.
Yes, sir.
Thanks for your hard work.
No, thank you all. Here's some breakfast.
Please take this around to everyone.
We're all on the lookout.
It's my fault for not noticing, but
we're almost out of salt. Can we get more?
Salt? You mean, salt?
Yes.
There's something moving at 10 o'clock.
Looks like an off-road cruiser.
Please confirm on the screen.
Maximum magnification.
28 kilometers ahead.
Ready the port-side machine guns!
The White Base will be landing.
Hey! Steady now...
Do butterflies fly in the desert?
Butterflies in the desert...?
Only the thorns of a cactus
fly in the desert.
He was sent by General Revil!
All right. I'll take over as driver.
Can he speak?
Sunmalo gave him some
emergency first aid, but...
I am Bright Noa,
the one responsible for the White Base.
Odessa Day is scheduled
for 5 days from now.
You're ordered to bring the White Base
across the Caspian Sea by then.
Odessa Day?
What's that?
It's when we'll start an offensive against the
main forces of M'Quve, Kycilia's subordinate.
M'Quve?!
The mines held by M'Quve
are considered...
...a strategic asset that will determine
the outcome of the war.
We'll attack them on Odessa Day.
Are you saying the White Base
will take part in the offensive?
We're not part of the military.
Right, Mr. Bright?
He's lost too much blood.
So, the White Base is being incorporated
into the regular forces.
What is it?
It's about that salt shortage.
Why haven't you noticed until now?
There was a direct hit on the stores
in the fighting the other day.
Our salt supplies were destroyed then.
Apparently, Zeon's strongest forces
are ahead of us.
It's doubtful we can get salt.
The lack of salt will affect
combat performance.
What should we do?
Amuro, aren't you finished yet?
It won't be done for some time.
How could I be finished?
It's still warm, so eat soon, okay?
Did we get in touch with General Revil?
Yes. Now they're saying we have no salt.
Eat, Amuro! Eat, Amuro!
Salt? You mean the kind you eat?
That's right.
You'll die if you don't get enough, right?
I guess...
Promise you'll eat.
Okay.
Amuro! Aren't you finished yet?
Almost done.
There! A saline lake,
along the old Silk Road.
A saline lake?
Yes. It's a lake that contains salt water.
If we go there, we may get some salt.
R-Really?
Operator. Can we head toward the lake?
As long as we don't run into M'Quve...
...then we won't have any problems.
Let's just assume there'll be less resistance
if we go around the lake.
That's so unlike you, Bright.
Don't laugh.
If our information is correct,
we should see the Trojan Horse soon.
Yes.
We should also contact Lord M'Quve.
This is Lady Kycilia's jurisdiction after all.
Open a line to Captain M'Quve.
Yes, sir!
Captain M'Quve is not here
at the moment.
He instructed me to provide you
with any necessary information.
I am Ensign Uragang.
Well-prepared as always.
I will contact you when I need to.
My regards to the captain.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Hear that, Hamon?
He certainly is well-prepared.
Who knows?
I hear that one must be cautious
around Lord M'Quve.
I'm just a guerrilla soldier.
I'll be headed back to space
once I avenge Lord Garma's death.
Well then, shall we spread
our net around here?
Yes.
A charming sound, isn't it?
Yes. Is it a precious item?
Northern Song Dynasty.
Huh?
What is it?
I've informed Ramba Ral
as per your instructions, sir.
I see.
Captain M'Quve.
What?
We have new information from intelligence.
The ship thought to be the Trojan Horse
has changed course.
How convenient.
They're moving away from my mines.
Wait a minute...
Uragang, inform Ramba Ral of this.
The sooner he gets rid of the Trojan Horse,
the less he'll be hanging around here.
No matter what happens,
we don't want Admiral Dozle to know...
...the truth about the mines I discovered.
Yes, sir.
M'Quve's underlings are quite dutiful...
...telling us the Trojan Horse
has taken a detour to avoid us.
Hmm... I don't know.
What do you think Lord M'Quve is up to?
You worry too much, Hamon.
- Hey! The lake's gone!
- Disappeared?!
It sure looks like there
was a lake here, but...
B-But this is...
Check the map! Is there no mistake?
Sir, there is no error.
But that doesn't make any sense!
Oh, no...
Mr. Tamura...
Just because I ran out of salt...
...I've made White Base wander off-course!
Zeon must have seen us by now!
Marker. Is there any other data on this lake?
I'll do a search.
Lob Lake... a salt lake.
Moves east to west like a pendulum
every 500 years.
It moves?!
How old is the map in our data?
Must be from before the war.
There haven't been any map-making
satellites since the war began.
Bright!
All right. Let's move. We'll pursue that lake.
Something's approaching!
Direction is 2 o'clock.
One vehicle, on the surface.
However, the type is unknown.
You can't tell what it is?
Can't you identify it from the speed,
altitude, or mass?
Just one enemy vessel?
It's too fast to be a Magella Attack.
Too small for a Gaw.
Amuro, can you head out?
It's hard to fight without knowing the enemy.
I don't know if this is a job for Gundam.
I'm launching the White Base!
All hands, level 1 battle stations!
Gundam, Guncannon,
and Guntank on stand-by!
We'll launch when we know a bit more.
Yes, sir!
All right. Let's go, everyone.
We're at level 1 battle stations.
Okay!
Are Ramba Ral, Acous,
and Cozun in the field yet?
Yes. Please take a look.
Our Gallop will make a broadside attack
on the enemy ship.
Lt. Ral and the two Zakus
will destroy it, like so.
Good.
The Gundam is...?!
Who's in the Gundam, Mr. Job?!
Ms. Sayla! She said she had special orders!
Are you saying she doesn't?
Of course there aren't any special orders!
Ms. Sayla, please get out of the Gundam!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Catapult engaged!
I'm launching!
I thought I figured this out
through the simulations, but...
I didn't think the G force would be this bad.
Port-side, return fire!
Prepare beam cannons!
Guncannon, Guntank!
Cover the Gundam!
Begin evasive maneuvers,
but don't stop firing!
Yes, ma'am!
He'll go into action any moment now.
Until then, keep the enemy engaged!
No matter what, I have to make contact
with a Zeon soldier.
An enemy?
A-A Zaku from the other side!
I'm aiming properly, but... no hits!
Never thought targeting would be so hard!
That pilot seems to be inexperienced.
Sorry, but I'm taking you out!
From the right!
Vulcans!
Ms. Sayla! Get up! Retreat!
If necessary, I'll transfer to the Gundam!
She probably turned the radio off.
A mobile suit for long-range support, huh?
Looks tough, but...
Go!
Did I get him?!
Ms. Sayla!
We haven't confirmed the hit yet!
Get back now!
Wh-Where's the pilot?!
A mobile suit isn't such an easy opponent.
Ms. Sayla, please stand back!
If the sand hadn't acted as a cushion...
...even this Gouf mobile suit
would have been finished!
He's not giving me a chance to aim!
Where is he?!
I've got to get him into grappling range!
C-Cozun! Don't be a fool! Get back!
No need to worry, Lieutenant Ral.
I'll capture this mobile suit.
The auto-balancer doesn't work!
Lieutenant Ral, just watch!
I'll plunder this mobile suit!
The main camera!
The cameras are being crushed!
Lieutenant, could you cut one of its
power pipes with your heat rod?
We'll take this one back to base.
If that new mobile suit
gets near the Gundam...
...there's no way we can save it!
Y-Yes!
But just keeping up with it...
...is taking everything I've got!
There he is!
I've split up the Zakus too much!
Are you all right, Cozun?!
I'll do my best to immobilize it on my own!
Acous! Can't you get past the red one
and over to Cozun?!
Ms. Sayla! Open the radio circuit!
You can't just use brute force!
Strength isn't enough!
Oh no! I'm out of ammo!
O-Oh no!
Acous! Acous!
Cozun, get back! Acous has been hit!
Acous?!
Has Acous been... killed?!
Get away from there!
Yes, sir!
Wh-What's going on?!
Lieutenant Ral!
Damn you!
Cozun! Cozun! Answer me! Cozun!
l-ls he dead?
Hamon! Can you hear me?!
Bring in the Gallop! Let's rendezvous!
Clamp, were you able to detect the Gouf?
We'll contact it in 50 seconds.
It looks like Acous and Cozun were killed.
We're going to have to retreat.
But... that's so frustrating, Ms. Hamon.
Why?
We have that new Zanzibar warship.
Why couldn't we...
How can we deploy something
that's still being tested?
And anyway, Admiral Dozle
thinks that Ramba Ral...
...has enough fighting strength to defeat
the Trojan Horse and the mobile suits._
And yet... I feel frustrated.
Without Lord M'Quve's cooperation,
we'll face some tough battles.
It's him!
I expect you treat prisoners
according to the Antarctic Treaty?
Of course.
However, you won't be fed well.
We can barely keep ourselves fed.
Same with us.
The higher-ups don't give a second thought
to us guys on the front lines.
Well, well. The warrior woman returns.
Ms. Sayla!
I'll see you on the bridge later.
Yes.
You wanted to prove that a woman
can fight as well as a man?
Was that your only reason?
Yes.
Ms. Sayla, someone as clever as you...
In any case, we must set an example
for the others.
Three days solitary confinement.
All right?
That's fine with me.
Ryu, if you please.
Ms. Sayla...
Meal for the prisoner?
Yes.
The two of you are not enough!
I'll do it, Fraw Bow.
Thank you.
Ms. Sayla...
Do you know what's happened to Char?
Char? You mean...
The Red Comet.
Won't you please tell me?
Char Aznable, right?
He lost his position
after he failed to protect Garma.
I heard he went back home.
I see. Thank you.
What were you talking about?
How much it would cost to buy me off.
It's only three days, so please be patient.
Don't worry about me, Mr. Ryu.
Just call for me if you need anything.
Thanks, Fraw Bow.
My big brother...
Char is my big brother...
I'm sure of it.
I'm so glad he's all right.
There! A lake!
Wow! It's so pretty!
Well! Who would've thought
it would move so far?
Now we can get our salt!
Cozun, the prisoner, attempts to escape
with the Federation's top secrets.
At the same time, the unrelenting power
of the Gouf's heat rod...
...burns away at the Guncannon's arm.
Can Amuro rescue Kai?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Amuro Deserts.
Next Time
Amuro Deserts
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...